There are strange phenomenon
in this world
that science is unable to explain.
When people came
face to face with them,
all they can do is tremble
upon the terror of the darkness.
But there are those who fight every day
to shine a ray of hope
into that chaotic darkness.
People call them...
Yokai Hunter.
This is the city, huh?
The city with the "Divine Tree"
that was the talk of variety shows.
Now then...
Which one will it be?
Demons or serpents?
(MOB MOB WOW!)
I realized that our youth is Grey
The origin of this uneasiness
Is yet unknown
Trains of emotions keep running
Through my brain
Struggling through this adolescence
Don't disturb my deep psyche
Who is that behind you?
Opposing ideas creates distortion
Exorcise all the sorrow
So, do what you can now
My life
Finally, break it down
(Want) Both greed
(Young) And honesty
(Burn) Are growing
(1) On this chest of mine
(Trance) I'm not waking up
(Chance) I want to wake up
(Stance) These two different faces of mine
(1) Are standing back-to-back
Taking things as it is
In this free relation where
We resent each other
Once these two become one
That smile becomes one
And only "1"(MOB MOB WOW!)
"1"(MOB MOB WOW!)
(MOB MOB WOW!)
One and only "1"(MOB MOB WOW!)
"1"
(MOB MOB WOW!)
One and only "1"
(Yokai Hunter Haruaki Amakusa appears!
~The Threat of Hyakki! ~)
Are there still anyone
who isn't assigned to a duty?
Okay, if you don't have
anything in mind,
then Niido, Sagure, Kageyama,
and Inukawa,
you're in charge of costumes.
This is the worst!
Costumes are the most important
part of a haunted house,
so please do your best.
Wouldn't sheets be enough?
Just wear a white sheet,
and say, "I'm a ghost~".
That's good enough, right?
Oh, then we don't have
to bother making anything!
Niido, you really are...
A freaking genius, man!
That's great, right, Mob?
We don't have to be stuck in sewing hell.
Is that really okay?
You're just giving a white cloth
to the ones portraying the ghosts.
As the ones responsible for the costumes,
shouldn't we try a bit harder?
Oh come on, Kageyama.
So can you make something?
Do you even have any good ideas?
If you have anything to say,
then say it.
Flapflapflapflapflap.
Do you get what he's saying?
(Progress until Mob explodes: 22%)
(Student Council Room)
Those that want to serve food
at the festival have to take a stool test,
please inform
all the class representatives.
President.
Hmm? What is it, Kageyama?
I think the themes are getting
a bit too extreme this year.
This concert plan is bound to cause noise
complaints from neighboring houses.
Not only that...
There's also the cross-dressing cafe!
It's just absurd!
It might be a cultural festival, but we
should keep our looks in moderation!
I think they're fine as long as
they keep the safety precautions.
What?!
I agree,
but just in case,
we'll give them another reminder.
Would that be satisfactory?
Yes...
Then time flies by.
The Culture Festival is now
two weeks away.
They're making steady progress...
If we do nothing, it'll be really bad.
This is bad...
Gotta think of a way
to raise the numbers...
The site traffic is low.
Thank you for waiting.
Oh, thanks.
So, what is it that
you want to talk about?
Actually...
(Night Middle School)
I see.
So you want to commute here?
This is pretty sudden.
I'm thinking of retaking
compulsory education.
It's a night school, so I will need
to finish my shift by 4 PM, so...
He's trying to improve himself, huh?
That's fine.
-Go at it.
-T-thank you very much!
Well, Mob's still here.
We'll probably be fine.
As for Dimple, I barely see him lately.
Probably should've put a collar on him.
Excuse me!
My name is Haruaki Amakusa,
a Yokai Hunter!
Mama, that guy...
Is what I'll say when I enter.
Excuse me. My name is...
Excuse mee...
Eexcusee me!
My name is Haruaki...
All right!
Exsqueeze me!
E-excuse me!
I'm Haruaki Amakusa!
What is your business here?
I am the one who hunts "Them".
Let's see, for now,
let's just call them...
They are "Those that dwell in the darkness",
and I am their hunter.
I came to this city to prevent
"That incident" from happening again.
I can barely understand
what he's saying.
I'm sorry, but we have a client
coming that needs exorcising.
Can you please wait outside?
I probably have no right to say this,
but that's one weird customer.
He's being questioned.
He's going to get taken
to the police station.
Thank you so very much,
Master Reigen.
Phew.
-Let's take a break, shall we?
-Oh, okay.
Are you free now?
It is I, Haruaki Amakusa.
He didn't get taken away...
Now then, about the "Dark Troops"...
I thought it was
"Those that dwell in the darkness".
"They" have more than one name.
Also, I suggest you don't say
those names easily.
You might get "Killed".
The "Vortex of Madness"
is most definitely spreading.
I would like to ask for your cooperation,
so we can sever the "Chain of Sadness".
Umm, dear customer,
I'm afraid I don't follow...
-I am not a customer.
-Huh?
I am the hunter of the darkness...
in the dark... uh...
"The hunter of those
that lurk within darkness."
Haruaki Amakusa, a Yokai Hunter.
Shut up!
I'm fed up listening to all
the pretentious words you're spitting out!
T-that's not what I'm...
Don't get carried away and purposely
pick hard to understand words, you idiot!
I don't have time to listen
to your nonsense!
Get to the point or get out! Otherwise,
I'll pluck that lock of hair of yours!
O-okay...
There are yokais threatening
peace in the world of men.
I, Haruaki Amakusa, am a Yokai Hunter,
therefore I hunt Yokai for a living.
For the traces of Yokai led me
to this Seasoning City, and thus...
A-ahem!
I'm going after the evil
Yokai group, Hyakki.
Their goal is to resurrect
the Great Yokai King,
and are preparing to drain a huge amount
of energy to achieve that goal.
His way of speaking went
back to normal midway.
Must be hard to talk like that.
The ominous aura grows day by day.
Honestly, I am worried.
How about you ask the police?
The police are not an option.
"They" would immediately...
...pull a "Violation of Swords and Firearms
Possession Control Law" and arrest me!
Of course they would.
A-anyway, I need your help
against the Hyakki...
Cut the bullcrap already!
I've had enough of playing
around with you.
We're running a business here, okay?
-Leave already, will you?
-You mean...
You will help as long as I pay
the consultation fee?
Would a million yen be enough?
You think this stack of notebook
papers would fool me?
Huh?
It's... It's real?!
My parents are rich,
and they support my activities.
-All right. Let's go, Serizawa.
-Huh?
We shall exterminate the "Hyakki!"
If the "Great Yokai King" is resurrected,
then the world would fall into "Darkness!"
We will erase the "Vortex of Madness,"
and sever the "Chain of Sadness!"
Y-yes, Sir!
I finally made friends.
Such happiness.
A Yokai Hunter is always alone
on their duty.
They always fight alone.
It has been so long
since I've felt human warmth.
I thank you.
Hey, Mob. What's wrong?
Oh, sorry. There's something
I want to discuss with you.
Oh, I'll listen after we finish this case.
Come with us.
What are we doing?
It's a Yokai extermination.
We're severing the Chain of Sadness.
Okay...?
Forgive me, young boy.
This is an "Emergency."
Women and children
shouldn't come with us.
Nah, it'll be fine for Mob.
Seems like this isn't the place, either.
Don't tell me he's actually
just a cosplayer.
Oh well, as long as he pays
the consultation fee.
Over there!
There's a slight Yokai presence
from there!
It's the place where we performed
an exorcism back then.
You completely vaporized
the evil spirit, right?
Only two weeks left...
I do feel some weird energy out of there.
Is that so?
Let's go, then.
Speaking of which, how much budget
do we have for the costumes, anyway?
This is absolutely the place.
No mistaking it.
(Progress until Mob explodes: 31%)
The space itself is warped.
It's the yokais doing, no doubt.
Curse you, Hyakki.
It appears they plan on turning
this place into their stronghold.
So the yokais are real?
So he's not just some
random cosplayer.
Plant roots?
What's wrong, Amakusa?
You're sweating a lot.
The truth is...
My experience in fighting yokais
is limited to one-on-one fights.
Even then, I always only
barely made it out alive.
Against a single opponent,
with full preparations on my side,
I only managed to exterminate it
after three days and nights.
But this time,
we're right inside the evil Yokai group
Hyakki's headquarters, it's way beyond...
What's wrong?!
This wall is pretty sticky, man.
We can use jelly to scare customers!
What now?!
Our way back!
It's sealed up.
I guess our only choice is to take out
the one warping the space itself.
You're pretty calm, Serizawa.
Oh, dark and closed spaces
calm me down.
We'll make it using cardboard
and duct tape,
then we'll have to measure
the height of the ghost actor...
Anyway, our only choice is forward.
Just accept your fate, Yokai Hunter.
My stomach is killing me...
Reigen, behind you!
There you are, Yokai!
O' spirit of something, something,
and something!
Grant me strength!
Holy Sword!
Kusanagi no Daihannya Kagemitsu!
My holy sword!
Oh, so the normal exorcism
method works.
What manner of power is that...?
They're all coming out
one after another.
They're coming in all directions!
We're in deep trouble.
I can't even think.
I'll weaken them by throwing salts.
I leave the rest to you,
Mob and Serizawa!
Yes, Sir!
Take this!
Salt Splash!
Oh, salt throwing could be
a good attraction.
I see.
If we put a ghost than can be exorcised,
then maybe even kids will find it fun.
T-that's...
The Four Hell Lords of Hyakki?!
And not to mention, behind them is...
...the Great Yokai King!
He's already resurrected!
Lowly humans.
They are the Four Hell Lords of Hyakki.
You shall be cast into
the abyss of terror.
It's over...
I'm so sorry I dragged you to this.
If this is that bad,
should we run away?
I don't think that's possible.
Yes, I don't think my design sense
is good enough to make one.
They took down two in an instant?!
Just who are they?
They are psychics.
How could such omnipotent powers
exist in this world?
H-how enviable.
Yeah, of course you'd thought that way.
But to them,
those powers aren't that useful.
You didn't just defeat members of Hyakki,
but even the Four Hell Lords.
Not bad, lowly humans.
However!
Don't think you can win against
the Great Yokai King!
W-what incredible powers...
Would you two be interested
in becoming Yokai Hunters?
Of course, I will be sure to give you
plenty of monthly salaries!
What?! H-hey, you two...!
I don't think I can do it.
I still want to study.
Sorry, I'm fully focused
on the cultural festival for now.
Cultural festival...?
Too bad for you, huh?
They're already full
from their daily life.
Amakusa, if you think you can make
everyone bend with stacks of money,
then you're sorely mistaken!
Forgive me, Reigen!
You believed my story
as a friend, and yet!
I tried to buy your cooperation
using money!
Please forgive my shameful conduct!
Wait, no!
I'm personally okay
with the consultation fee... ack!
Ahem...
Y-yes, I see.
As long as you understand.
Reigen, I am truly grateful.
Now that I look at it,
that's quite the striking design.
Maybe we can make a stuffing out of it
and sell it for profit?
They're an apparition, so...
He'll turn to dust soon, too.
I see...
That's it!
So,
he's actually a real Yokai Hunter.
Some jobs are really out there, huh?
Let's have ramen and go home.
Oh, I have something I have to do, so...
Oh? So what was that thing
you want to discuss again?
It's okay, I found a solution.
I'll be going.
Mob solved a problem by himself...
Inukawa, I got an idea
about the costume.
Can you come to the classroom
early tomorrow?
What?! I thought we decided
on the white sheets!
No, I think we should try our best.
Everyone is working hard
on their duty, after all.
And so, the day of
the cultural festival arrives.
The reaction to the costume Mob
and Inukawa made were rather mediocre,
but there were no complaints.
As for the reaction from
the customers...
I see.
It's pretty well made
for middle schooler level.
That's quite the striking design...
-I'm glad we did it.
-Yeah, I guess.
That was pretty tiring, though.
Yeah, I'm glad we did it.
(Today's Maids)
Thank you for waiting.
Here's your Forest Bear
Lickety-Lick Soda,
and your Dreaming Hoppity
Hop Bunny Cola.
Oh my, so cute!
All the boys are wearing maid outfits!
Let me take a picture!
Enjoy your stay...
We have another customer!
Hey there, Ritsu...
That's one heck of an outfit
you have there...
Well, it kinda fits you, though.
(Spirits and Such Consultation Office)
All right, that should do it.
This should increase traffic.
The blue light shined
Dazzling my eye at 01:30 AM
Even as I swiped the page over,
The smiles of friends besides me remain
Yes, I want someone to understand
All the colorless and transparent wishes
All the breath stuck within
The depth of my heart
Suddenly flowed out
Bringing my consciousness back
I remember the days hung dry
The very normal days passed by
Even if reality is corrupted
The sky we saw together
Was definitely real
It's harder to understand than
The grammar on the blackboard
The story that disappears
Under 24 hours makes me sad and lonely
It's so hard, and I find myself
On the verge of giving up again and again
But I...
The current me will no longer give up
Overflowing emotions on my sleeve,
Running through worry and doubt
Nobody has decided if the future is 0 or 100,
So I'll paint over them myself
Even if my existence itself can't be proven,
If this world struck me in my heart
I will flood it with cobalt blue
What? Mob is starting to get popular?
He got super popular among women,
and was even elected as a founder?
All right, go at it, Mob!
Next on episode three of
Mob Psycho 100 III,
"Conceited ~100%~"
Recording it?
That's also a wise decision.